[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas：那么让我们谈谈测试，所以异步系统中的测试是
&gt;&gt; Douglas: So let's talk about testing, so testing in asynchronous systems is
很棘手，因为大多数测试框架都带有这样的东西。
tricky because most test frameworks come with stuff like this right.
你得到了一些断言，你得到了一个描述性的信息和一些东西
You've got some assertion and you've got a descriptive message and something
你将在实际值中得到一个期望值，如果它们匹配，那么它就是好的。
you'll have an expected value in an actual value and if they match, then it's good.
如果它们不匹配，那就不好了。
And if they don't match, it's bad.
只是这在异步系统中不起作用，对吧？
Except this doesn't work in asynchronous systems, right?
因为你不能等待实际值。
Because you can't wait for the actual value.
实际的价值可能不会发生，直到许多变成未来和
The actual value might not happen until many turns into the future and
这根本行不通。
this just doesn't work.
更重要的是，我对我们做测试的方式有一个普遍的问题。
More than that though, I have a problem with the way we do testing in general.
在这一点上，我们试图猜测
In that, we're trying to guess what
期望值是将识别bug的值。
the expected value is which is going to identify the bug.
但我们的大多数错误都发生在事物的相互作用中。
But most of our errors happen in the interactions of things.
找出一堆东西会在哪里汇聚在一起
And finding where a bunch of things are going to come together and
在发生故障的一点进行交互。
interact at the one point that fails.
要找到那一点几乎是不可能的。
It's virtually impossible to find that one point.
所以你真正想要的是有一个网格，一个拖网，在那里你会有很多
So what you really want is to have a grid, a dragnet where you're gonna have a much
在可能性空间上随机分布的更大的空间阵列。
larger array of spaces that's distributed randomly over the possibility space.
你把它们都挑出来，希望你能
And you pick them all out and hopefully then you'll
提高发现错误的可能性。
improve the likelihood that you're gonna find the error.
只是你不想这么做，对吧？
Except you don't wanna do that, right?
你想要写一千倍的测试用例，
You wanna have to write a thousand times more test cases,
其中大多数无论如何都不太可能成功找到任何东西。
most of which are unlikely to succeed in finding anything anyway.
这是一个巨大的努力，没有人会想这样做。
That's a huge amount of effort, no one's gonna wanna do that.
再加上如果模型有变化，
Plus if there's a model change,
这意味着你现在必须更新数以千计的测试，没有人会这么做。
it means you now have to update thousands more tests and nobody is gonna do that.
当我看到约翰·休斯的演讲时，我对此感到有点绝望
And it was kind of despairing about that, when I saw a talk by John Hughes of
查尔默斯大学关于一个叫QuickCheck的东西，我认为它很聪明。
Chalmers University about something called QuickCheck which I thought was brilliant.
为了给您提供相关的上下文，QuickCheck是在Haskell中开发的。
So to give you the context about that, QuickCheck was developed in Haskell.
Haskell是爱丁堡大学开发的一种语言
Haskell is a language that was developed at the University of Edinburgh and
它是一种纯函数式编程语言。
it is a pure functional programming language.
他们所说的纯粹是因为这是一种没有副作用的语言
That they say pure in that it's a language without side effects and
这有好有坏，但也有好的一面。
that's good and bad but there's good things about it.
关于Haskell的另一件事是
The other thing about Haskell is,
它可能是世界上任何语言中最好的类型系统。
it's got maybe the best type system of any language in the world.
而不是在Java中指定类型
Instead of having something like in Java where you specify the type
对于每一件小事，你几乎没有指定任何东西的类型。
of every little thing, you specify the types of almost nothing.
相反，有一个推理引擎作为编译器的一部分运行，它
And instead there is an inference engine that runs as part of the compiler which
通过查找程序中的所有内容，尝试确定所有内容。
goes through looking up everything in the program trying to determine everything is.
如果你是那些人中的一员，如果你想在没有行动的情况下行动，那么你必须是那些人中的一员
If you're one of those, if you want to act without then you must be one of those and
继续这样做，试图解决整个程序。
so on and keep doing that trying to solve the entire program.
如果它发现了不一致的地方，
And if it gets to a point where it finds an inconsistency,
它可以停止，这里出了问题。
it can stop and something's wrong here.
困难之处在于
And the difficulty with that is that where it
发现它的不一致可能与你实际犯下错误的地方相隔数英里。
finds its inconsistency may be miles away from where you actually made your mistake.
所以要编译一个程序真的很有挑战性，但是
And so getting a program to compile can be really challenging, but
理论是，一旦你让一个程序编译，它就能保证运行。
the theory is that once you get a program to compile it's guaranteed to run.
但这并不是因为它证明了潜在错误的类别是无限的
Except it's not because it turns out the class of potential errors is infinitely
比即使是世界上最好的人也能发现的一类错误更大
bigger than the class of errors that could be found even by the world's best
键入系统。
type system.
所以你仍然需要测试
So you still have to test and
这些人想出了一个非常好的测试方法。
these guys came up with a really nice way of doing tests.
不是编写具体的实际与预期的比较，
Instead of writing specific compare actual versus expected,
相反，您可以编写一个函数，如果系统正常工作，则该函数将为真。
instead you write a function which will be true if the system is working correctly.
因此，他们将这些属性称为系统
So in that they call those properties that the system
将为真，如果这些属性保持不变，则工作正常。
will be true is working correctly if these properties hold.
因此，然后QuickCheck将生成随机数据
And so and then QuickCheck will generate random data and
把它们扔到你的函数上，试着反驳你的断言。
throw them at your functions and try to disprove your assertion.
因此他们可以在那里获得巨大的覆盖，甚至能够
And so they can get tremendous coverage there, even able to
调试实时系统，这是非常困难的事情。
debug real time systems which is something that is really, really hard to do.
所以我想，哇，我们应该为JavaScript买一个这样的东西。
So I thought, wow, we should get one of those for JavaScript.
所以我写了一个，叫做JSCheck。
So I wrote one, it's called JSCheck.
JSCheck提供了两个好东西，一个是案例生成。
JSCheck provides two nice things, one is case generation.
所以它会为你生成随机的测试用例
So it'll generate random test cases for you and
它还支持翻转测试。
it also supports testing over turns.
所以你可以用它来测试节点中的东西，你可以用它来测试浏览器中的东西，
So you can use it to test stuff in node, you can use it to test things in browsers,
您可以使用它来测试同步和异步函数。
you can use it to test synchronous and asynchronous functions.
所以这是一个带有一些功能的小型库，
So it's a small library that comes with some functions,
这些是一些有趣的。
these are a few of the interesting ones.
最重要的一个是索赔，我们将在一分钟内更多地讨论这个问题。
The most important one is claim, we'll talk more about that in a minute.
这就是你提出关于系统的要求的地方。
That's where you make a claim about how about the system.
如果它正在工作，工作正常，那么这就是真的。
If it's working through, working correctly then this would be true.
然后您可以告诉您检查您所做的所有声明
You can then tell to check all of the claims that you've made so
远，你也可以给它加一个时间限制。
far and you can also put a time limit on it.
所以它会同时开始所有的测试，他们都必须完成
So it will start all the test simultaneously and they all have to finish
在一定的时间内，如果他们不这样做，那么你可以记录下来。
by a certain amount of time, if they don't then you can record that.
这一点非常重要，因为我们的系统现在的工作方式
And that's really important because, the way our systems work now getting
正确的答案，但花费的时间太长，无法与错误的答案区分开来。
the right answer but taking too long is indistinguishable from the wrong answer.
因此，我们还需要能够测试性能
And so, we need to be able to test performance as well and
这是同步测试框架不做的事情。
that's something that the synchronous testing frameworks don't do.
然后我们可以在事情完成后得到一个回调
Then we can get a callback when the thing is done and
我们会得到所有发生的事情的完整报告。
we'll get a full report about everything that happened.
我们还可以在发生错误时获得每个错误的回调，并且
We can also get a callback on each error as the errors occur and
您可以对该回调进行编程，以将您带到调试器中。
you can program that callback to take you into the debugger.
因此，当您发现bug时，您就处于可以立即修复它的上下文中。
So as you're finding bugs, you're in the context where you can fix it immediately.
这就是声明函数，它接受一个描述性的名称，它接受一个谓词
So this is the claim function, it takes a descriptive name, it takes a predicate
功能为布尔值，如果您的系统工作正常，则该值为真。
function as a Boolean which will be true if your system is working correctly.
它需要一个签名，它是一个数组
And it takes a signature which is an array
类型描述符的类型，用于描述谓词函数的参数。
of type descriptors which describes the parameters to the predicate function.
这里有一个例子，我们将比较旧代码和新代码。
So here's an example, we're going to compare the old code with the new code.
我们的谓词将采用一个verdict函数和一个参数，并且
Our predicate will take a verdict function and an argument and
然后我们将确定
we will then determine that the old code for
该参数的作用与新代码相同。
that argument does the same thing as the new code.
我们告诉它参数是一个整数。
And we tell it that that argument is an integer.
所以当我们让这东西检查的时候。
So when we tell this thing to check.
它将生成随机整数并将它们抛向该函数，
It will generate random integers and throw them at that function,
试图反驳我们的断言，你可以设置你想要的数量。
trying to disprove our assertion and you can set as many as you want.
所以使用系统的所有努力都是通过编写这些谓词和
So all of the effort in using the system is in writing these predicates and
有很多方法可以做到。
there are lots of ways you could do it.
一个是，在这种情况下，我们将旧代码与新代码进行比较。
One is, in this case we're comparing the old code against the new code.
所以当我们迁移系统时，
So as we're migrating the system,
我们可以确保我们没有改变任何东西的行为。
we can make sure that we haven't changed the behavior of anything.
另一种可以做到这一点的方法是，如果你有对称的操作，例如，
Another way you could do it is if you have symmetrical operations, for example,
如果你在写编码器和解码器。
if you're writing an encoder and a decoder.
通常情况下，编码的解码应该等于原始
It's usually the case that the decode of the encode should be equal the original
事情，所以我们可以测试，对于一大类试验来说，这实际上是真的。
things, so we can test that that's actually true for a large class of trials.
我们可以生成对称的事物对，就像我们可以生成信用和
We can generate symmetric pairs of things like we can generate a credit and
借方，你知道两者都使用随机值来确保一切平衡。
a debit, you know both using random values make sure everything balances.
在某些情况下，您可能只是在某件事情上抛出了很多随机事务。
And in some cases you just might throw a lot of random transactions at something.
在每一次之后，对所有的数据结构进行深度诊断，
And after each one, run a deep diagnostic of all your data structures,
确保一切仍然一致。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：SO
make sure everything is still consistent. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So
这看起来像是实现了什么？
what would this look like implemented?
我不明白什么是判决。&gt；&gt；Douglas：我们来看看
I don't understand what verdict is. &gt;&gt; Douglas: We'll look at
一分钟内垂直。
the vertical in a minute.
因此，verdict是正在使用的回调
So verdict is the callback that is being used in
箱子。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：好的。
the cases. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Okay.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：是这样
&gt;&gt; Douglas: So it
附带了一个小型说明符的库。
comes with a small library of specifiers.
您可以将其中的每一个放在描述符数组中，描述符数组中包含我们想要的类型
You can put each of these in the descriptor array of what types we want to
抛给我们的谓词和
throw to our predicate and
它会尝试，它会生成这些类型的每个值的随机值。
it'll try, it'll generate values random values of each of these types.
所以，如果你需要布尔值，如果你需要整数，数字，对象，任何东西。
So if you need Booleans, if you need integers, numbers, objects, whatever.
它会制造随机的东西然后分发出去。
It'll make random things and pass them out.
如果它变了，这些也可以用有趣的方式堆肥。
If it turns, and these are also compostable in interesting ways.
例如，如果您想要随机的社会保险号码。
For example, if you want random social security numbers.
我可以说我想用三位数来加强，然后是破折号和
I can say I want to strengthen with three digits and then a dash and
一个破折号中的两个数字，以此类推。
two digits in a dash and so on.
或者如果我需要一个包含三个元素的数组，其中第一个
Or if I need an array containing three elements where the first
元素是一个整数，第二个元素是一个介于0和100之间的数字，并且
element is an integer and the second is a number between zero and 100 and
第三个是我可以得到的字符串。
the third is a character string I can get that.
或者我需要一个对象，其中具有left属性的top属性和
Or I need an object where with the left property a top property and
从列表中选择的颜色。
a color selected from a list.
或者我需要一个具有可变数量属性的对象，其中每个属性都是
Or I need an object with a variable number of properties where each property is
一个四个字母的名称，每个值都是一个布尔值，我可以做到这一点。
a four letter name and each value is a Boolean, I can do that.
有很多方法来组成这些和
There are lots of ways to compose these and
如果结果是有一些您需要的特定测试数据，则不是
if it turns out there is some particular test data that you need that's not
很容易从这些组成，你可以写你自己的。
easily composed from these, you can write your own.
它是一个发电机，和你一直在写的发电机一模一样。
And it's a generator, exactly like the generators you've been writing.
因此，您有一个函数，它返回一个函数，当您每次调用它时，
So you have a function that returns a function that when, each time you call it,
你会得到下一个值。
you'll get the next value.
您可以编写其中一个来生成所需的所有随机测试数据。
You can write one of those to generate all the random test data that you need.
异步工作的原因是由于verdict函数。
The reason this works asynchronously is because of the verdict function.
每次检查开始时，都会传递一个用于
Every check when it begins, is passed a verdict function that it is used to
返回其结果，判决只是一个延续。
return its result and the verdict is just a continuation.
这只是一个回叫，允许试验延长许多回合。
It's just a call back which allows the trials to be extended over many turns.
因为我们也可以对此设定时间限制，
And because we can also put time limits on this,
现在每个试验都有三种可能的结果。
we now have three possible outcomes for every trial.
我们可以看到通行证，我们可以看到失败者，或者我们可以看到失败者。
We can see a pass, we can see a fail or we can see a lost.
丢失意味着我们在时间到期之前没有收到报告。
Lost means we did not get a report before the time expired.
而这些有时也同样重要，就像通过和失败一样。
And those are sometimes as important, as the passes and fails.